

PALASH CHAUHAN

Ph: +91 8375961884

Email: palashchauhan2@gmail.com

C-919, Gaur Global Village Crossing Republic Ghaziabad.

OBJECTIVE

Oracle cer fied professional (OCJP) with 3 years 1 months of experience as a Full Stac Developer. Working on cu ng edge technologies Seeking opportuni es to u lize my knowledge, skills & abili es for groo ming my personality and to provide my services to the progressive organiza on.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

 HCL Technologies ,Noida Senior So ware Engineer (May 2019 – II date)

Pure So ware ,Noida So ware Engineer (February 2018 – April 2019) (October 2017 – February 2018)

3. Nebel Infotech, Gurgaon Java Trainee

PROFESSIONAL RESPONSIBILITIES

- Strong experience and exper se as a Full Stack developer and Proficient in HCL' inhouse BPM tool designing
 process from scratch and integra ng with RPA.
- Well Versed with different design pa erns to develop Java applica ons like Factory, Service etc.
- Hands on experience with front end technologies like Angular, HTML5, Bootstrap and CSS.
- Hands on experience with Database opera ons using SQL.
- Experience on working with Spring and Spring MVC frameworks.
- Reduced overall CPU u liza on by **20%** in one of the recent projects undertaken.
- Developing Business solu ons for U.S based clients from scratch using HCL BPM tool and integra ng it with RPA.
- Having worked with the Embedded team as Java developer, I have hands-on experience with x86 and x64 machines.
- Designing Business so ware solu on from scratch for one of 'Big Four' Irish banks. Handled modules single handedly.
- Have rich experience on **DOCKER** resolving cross pla orm dependencies.
- Sun Cer fied Java Programmer. (SCJP version7)
- AWS Cer fica on on "Ge ng Started with AWS Security, Iden ty and Compliance

- A ended training " Camunda Essen als " provided by HCL for ge ng hands on for upcoming BPM projects in Pipeline
- Managed overall deployment, release, upstreaming using Docker images and contributed in open source projects.
 - Quick learner with the ability to grasp new technologies
- Possess good communica on skills, self-mo vated, proac ve, task oriented and good team player

ACADEMIC QUALIFICATIONS

- Bachelor of Technology (May 2012–May 2016) From G.L. Bajaj Instute of Technology and Management with 65.96%
- Senior Secondary Examina on (PCM) (2010-2011) From Modern School Noida with 61% Secondary Examina on (2009-2010) From Ryan Interna onal School, Noida with 83%

CORE COMPETENCIES

- Java Technologies: Java, J2EE and Res ul, JDBC, JSP, JSTL, Servlets
- Applica on Server: JBOSS, Tomcat HCL BPM Tool including Docker Databases: SQL Frameworks/API's: JPA, Hibernate
- Code Development Tools: Eclipse, IntelliJ, Atom
- Scrip ng/Markup Languages: HTML/HTML 5, CSS/CSS3, Angular, XML
- Version Controlling tools: GIT
- Opera ng Systems: Windows 8/10, Linux
- Design Pa erns: Singleton, Factory
- Frameworks: Spring, Spring MVC, Hibernate
- **J2EE:** Servlets, JSP, JDBC
- Web Services: REST Documenta on Tools: MS Word, MS Excel

PROJECTS

Project Name: Global Ticketing Tool

Dura on: May 2020 – till date

Synopsis: Xerox Holdings Corporation is an American corporation that sells print and digital document products and services in m ore than 160 countries. They needed a ticketing tool to manage the tickets raised by the end user. HCL BPM tool was used to d evelop the project.

Responsibilities:

- Designed the process of the project from scratch using a process modeller in **HCL BPM** tool.
- Designed worksteps and various decision making steps and mapping with external tables in the database for saving and fetching.
- Using **Angular** form was designed.
- Handled single handedly email func onality module in which email is triggered when cket is assigned to the user.
- SLA breach procedure in SQL was wri en where email is triggered when the user has not worked on certain ckets.
 - Periodically customer requests were handled to add new features like new field add, change in procedures etc Interac on with client team and ac vely hosted walkthrough/sign-off mee ngs.
- Regression tes ng a er every new release/Prod load.
- Par cipa ng in various client status and review mee ngs.
- Ac vely involved with management for communica ng status of me cri cal deliveries.

Project Name: Invoice Processing Unit(AP process)

Dura on: Jan 2020 – Mar 2020

Synopsis: Xerox corporation needed a BPM solution which must also be integrated with RPA to process the Invoices. This was a solution where every day more than 10k invoices were processed.

Responsibilities:

- Designed the process of the project from scratch using a process modeller in HCL BPM tool.
- Wrote func onality to Reduce overall CPU u liza on by 20% while processing invoices.
- Email func onality was designed.
- Angular was used to design overall form.
- Designed worksteps and various decision making steps and mapping with external tables in the database for saving and fetching.
- Template genera on module was designed.
- Process variable mapping was done to get queue view at each work step.

Project Name: S.B.A. Bank of Ireland

Dura on: May 2019 – Dec 2019

Synopsis: Bank of Ireland Group plc is a commercial bank o peration in Ireland and one of the traditional 'Big Four' Irish banks. Historically the premier banking organisation in Ireland, Founded in 1783 needed a BPM solution to manage their operations.

Responsibilities:

- Entered the project when it was in the developing stage.
- Modified the process route to add new features.
- Handled template genera on func onality. Signature func onality was handled
- Wrote func onality by which files consis ng customer data was processed and converted into work items in which Bank employees can work.
- New customer requests were managed and added new features as per demand.

PERSONAL DETAILS

Date of Birth: 1st September, 1993 Languages Known: English, Hindi

(Palash Chauhan)